Jacob Nguyen

nguyenvjacob@gmail.com | 780-263-0748

Summary

Keen and driven software engineer candidate with experience in research, data analysis, software and web development, making products for clients and the petroleum industry. Recent graduate with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science with a willingness to learn.

Education

University of Alberta Sept. 2019 - May 2023

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Edmonton, AB

Work Experience

Stellar Machining & Manufacturing Inc Computer Numerical Control Machinist

Edmonton, AB May 2023 - Present (Full-Time) Sept. 2022 - May 2023 (Part-Time) May 2022 - Sept. 2022 (Full Time)

- Utilize computer programming software to write operating instructions for computer numerically controlled precision machinery such as mills and lathes.
- Troubleshoot software and mechanical issues that arise, and correct these issues to ensure seamless operation, resulting in a notable improvement in the overall efficiency of operations.
- Conduct quality control, ensuring products meet specifications and quality standards, resulting in commendations from stakeholders for maintaining top-tier product standards.

Skills

Programming: C, C++, Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, GitHub

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Android

Software Packages: Numpy, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Scipy, Matplotlib

Data Analysis: Modeling and analyzing linear and logistic regression, data visualization

Projects

Lifestyle Optimizer | Full Stack Development | Java, JavaScript, Firebase

- Led a team in developing a social media application focused on habit tracking.
- Created a feature that enables users to follow one another, geotag location and share their progress, allowing for user interaction and engagement.
- Developed account protection, ensuring user information remains confidential and secure using Google's Firebase platform, leading to a seamless user login using a Google account.

Covid-19 Data Analysis | Back End Development | Python, MySQL

- Developed a program for in-depth analysis of a Covid-19 impact dataset.
- Leveraged statistical analysis and data visualization, to produce valuable insights and trends about the pandemic's impact.